# Daniel Taylor, Reservoir Engineer, P.E.

Address: 13551 Spendlove Dr, Anchorage, AK 99516 Email: amboydan@protonmail.com Cell: (907) 947-8051

## RESERVOIR ENGINEER

Professional Petroleum Engineer (AK: 143467) and SPEC with experience in conventional oil and gas reservoirs under various depletion mechanisms. Experience at multiple levels in reservoir lifecycle, from quantifying initial volumetrics, evaluating PVT, and SCAL data to secondary recovery and work over operations in brown field areas. Organized, thorough, and efficient approach to creating field development plans in multiple reservoirs, and execution of plans. Expertise in aggregating field and well history data to build informative distributions. Expertise in evaluating new completion and well designs which maximize recovery as well as recompleting old wells to increase rate and reserves. Currently pursuing Associate Actuary designation (Exam P and FM Completed) to aid in asset portfolio analysis.

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

# Kenai Team Optimization Engineer

# September 2021- Present

Develop and maintain GAP, Prosper, MBAL models for Kenai Gas Storage Reservoirs; Kenai Field, Swanson River

- Kenai Team reservoir engineer tasked with optimization and surveillance of primary Cook Inlet storage reservoir deliverability.
- Building and maintaining custom applications for tracking, modeling, and forecasting rate add projects. Develop model based approach to forecasting market deliverability health.

## Milne Point Kuparuk Reservoir Engineer

## November 2019- September 2021

Developing new economic prospects and opportunities within a mid-life waterflood; Milne Point, Kuparuk, Sag River

- Kuparuk reservoir engineer tasked with infield development via grass roots and sidetrack drill well candidates targeting the most economic un-swept acreage field wide.
- Maximizing recovery factor and acceleration of rate throughout all fault blocks via detailed analysis of pattern sweep efficiency and injection water placement.

#### **Swanson River Reservoir Engineer**

#### January 2015 – December 2019

Creating and executing detailed field development plan for a mature gas flooded reservoir; Swanson River, Hemlock Oil

- Re-introduced gas flood by planning and executing on 2 gas injectors targeting high oil saturation fault blocks.
- Lead engineer tasked with quantifying remaining oil and gas reserves within each fault block of all heavily gas flooded Hemlock oil benches.

#### Ninilchik Reservoir Engineer

#### January 2015 - December 2017

Initializing grass roots drill well program targeting previously undeveloped Tyonek sands; Ninilchik, Tyonek Gas

- Lead engineer planning and executing drill wells within depletion and water drive gas reservoirs.
- Completed dynamic statistical model for reservoir depletion forecasting and reserves allocation.

#### **Cook Inlet Offshore Operations Engineer**

#### January 2013 - January 2015

Executing well intervention operations and supporting facility development projects;

• Lead operations engineer generating well intervention procedures, contracting required personnel, and continuously driving down costs.

# **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Petroleum Experts Suite, IHS Harmony, IHS Welltest, CMG, PETRA, ArcGIS, QGIS, Microsoft office suite, VBA, R, JavaScript, SQL, MongoDB, SAS.

#### **EDUCATION**

M.S. in Applied Statistics, Texas A&M

B.S. in Petroleum Engineering, University of Alaska Fairbanks

May 2023

May 2010

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Hilcorp Energy Company, Petroleum Engineer
National Oilwell Varco, Drilling Solutions Engineer
Schlumberger, Open Hole Wireline Engineer
United States Marine Corps, Sergeant of Marines

January 2013 - Current
March 2012 - January 2013
June 2010 - January 2012
August 1999 - August 2004